<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-09-09T23:24:48+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aman Desai</title><entry><title type="html">ProtonMail – Encrypted Email Service.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/proton-mail" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ProtonMail – Encrypted Email Service." /><published>2019-09-09T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-09-09T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/proton-mail</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/proton-mail">&lt;h1 id=&quot;think-your-e-mails-private-think-again--protonmail--encrypted-email-service&quot;&gt;Think your e-mail’s private? Think again | ProtonMail – Encrypted Email Service.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25yrs ago, scientists at &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.cern/&quot;&gt;CERN&lt;/a&gt; created World Wide Web (WWW).Since then, the internet has transformed the way we do business, the way we communicate, and even the way we leave. In many ways, the ideas that gave birth to Google, Facebook, Twitter and many other tech-giants have now really transformed our lives, and this has brought us many real benefits such as more connected society. However, there is a downside effect to this. A huge amount of one’s personal information is online, and we add to this information, every single time we post on social media, each time we do a google search and each time we send an email. These data reveal what we think, what we do, where we go and almost everything. The more scary part is, this data now lasts forever! Now your data can and will outlive you. What has happened is, we have lost control over data, and also our privacy. There is one place where something about privacy can be done. That’s e-mail. Since email are not hosted by a particular company, there is something which can be done. That is, Encryption!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your email is nothing but a collection of letters printed on a post card, which can be read by everyone along the way(Email Provider, ISP, etc.). Solution to this problem is, encrypting email, and passing it along with a given key. But now, there is again a problem. Now, your postcard is in the lock, but again with key attached to it. Anyone can apply that key and open the lock, resulting in loss of privacy again. Here comes ProtonMail into action!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;protonmail&quot;&gt;ProtonMail:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ProtonMail is the world’s largest secure email service, developed by CERN and MIT scientists. We are open source and protected by Swiss privacy law. ProtonMail is incorporated in Switzerland and all our servers are located in Switzerland. This means all user data is protected by strict Swiss privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;protonmail-website&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protonmail.com/&quot;&gt;ProtonMail Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-principle-of-protonmail-very-interesting&quot;&gt;Working principle of ProtonMail (Very Interesting):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/blog/encrypted-protected-explanation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BobAlice Explaination&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve above discussed problem, ProtonMail came up with a solution. What they did is they generated two keys for each user, each being mathematically connected. Let us consider that Bob is sending mail to Alice. Now, Alice has two keys (Public Key and Private Key). Public key is sent to Bob which is used to encrypt mail. That mail can only be decrypted by some unknown, self-encrypted mathematical modification. That modification is the other key which is with Alice. From the whole scenario, it turns out that the key is only with Alice. Thus, only Alice can decrypt mail and view its contents, neither the provider, nor the government &lt;b&gt;Not even sender (Bob)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Think your e-mail’s private? Think again | ProtonMail – Encrypted Email Service.</summary></entry></feed>